Finding Aid for Provost and Executive Vice-President for Academic Affairs (University of Michigan) Central Files
Bentley Historical Library
- Central Files
  - 1969-1970
    - Alphabetical Files
      - Kellogg Foundation (Box 23)
      - Kelsey Museum of Archaeology (Box 23)
      - King (Martin Luther) Fund (Box 23)
      - L-General (Box 24)
      - Latin American Studies (Box 24)
      - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration (Box 24)
      - Law School
        - Allen, Francis A., Dean (Box 24)
        - Correspondence (Box 24)
      - Legislative Intern Program (Box 24)
      - Lelong, Donald C. (Office of Institutional Research) (Box 24)
      - Lesch, James E. (Assistant to VPAA) (Box 24)
      - Letters to Deans (Box 24)
      - Library Council (Box 24)
      - Library, University (Box 24)
      - Library Science, School of (Box 24)
      - Lists (miscellaneous) (Box 24)
      - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of
        - General (Box 24)
        - Administrative Board (Box 24)
        - Admissions (Box 24)
        - Assembly (Box 24)
        - Associate Deans (Box 24)
        - Astronomy, Department of (Box 24)
        - Committees (Box 24)
        - Departments, 3 folders (Box 24)
        - Financial Status (Box 24)
        - Hays, William, Dean (Box 24)
        - Museums (Box 24)
        - Review (Box 24)
        - Speech, Department of: Theatre Department Proposal (Box 24)
        - Study (Box 24)
      - Lovell, Robert G., MD (faculty/staff complaint) (Box 295)
      - M-General (Box 24)
      - Massalias, Byron G. (faculty/staff complaint) (Box 295)
      - Mc-General (Box 24)
      - McFarland, Arthur (Box 24)
      - Medical Center
        - Board-in-Control (Box 24)
        - Compliance (Box 24)
        - Correspondence (Box 24)
        - Planning (Box 24)
      - Medical School
        - Associate Deans (Box 24)
        - Correspondence (Box 24)
        - Deans Hubbard and Gronvall (Box 24)
        - Gronvall, John A., Acting Dean (Box 24)
        - Hubbard, William N., Dean (Box 24)
      - Medicinal Chemistry (Box 25)
      - Memberships (Box 25)
      - Mental Health Research Institute (MHRI) (Box 25)
      - Mental Retardation, Institute for the Study of
        - Committees (Box 25)
        - Correspondence (Box 25)
        - Cohen and Thoburn (Box 25)
        - Cruickshank, Dr. William M (Box 25)
        - Michigan Mental Retardation Research Committee (Box 25)
        - Plymouth State Home Agreement (Box 25)
      - Mexican-American Students (Box 25)
      - Michigan (miscellaneous) (Box 25)
      - Michigan Academy (Box 25)
      - Michigan Association for Regional Medical Programs (Box 25)
      - Michigan Bell Telephone (Box 25)
      - Michigan Chronicle (Box 25)
      - Michigan Council of State College Presidents (Box 25)
      - Michigan Daily (Box 25)
        (see Daily, Michigan)
      - Michigan Society of Fellows (Box 25)
      - Michigan State University (Box 25)
      - Mott (C.S.) Children's Hospital (Box 25)
      - Mott Foundation (Box 25)
      - Museum of Art
        - Sawyer, Charles, Director (Box 25)
        - Search Committee (Box 25)
      - Music, School of
        - General (Box 25)
        - Britton, Allen P., Acting Dean (Box 25)
        - Correspondence (Box 25)
        - Wallace, James B., Dean (Box 25)
      - N-General (Box 25)
      - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASULGC) (Box 25)
      - National Defense Education Act (NDEA) (Box 25)
      - National Music Camp (Box 25)
      - Natural Resources, School of
        - General (Box 25)
        - Dean Search (Box 295)
        - Master of Natural Resources Degree (Box 25)
        - Preston, Stephen B., Dean (Box 25)
        - Review (Box 25)
        - Review Committee (Box 25)
        - Review Committee Report (Box 25)
      - Negro (Box 25)
      - Neurosciences Program (Box 25)
      - Newell, Barbara W. (Acting Vice President for Student Affairs) (Box 25)
      - Non-reappointment Procedures (Box 25)
      - Norman, A. G (Box 25)
      - North Central Association
        - General (Box 25)
        - Review (Box 25)
      - Nursing, School of
        - Accreditation (Box 25)
        - Correspondence (Box 25)
        - Russell, Rhoda R., Dean (Box 25)
      - O-General (Box 25)
      - Occupational Therapy Program (Box 25)
      - Olson, Clifford D. (Biostatistics) (Box 25)
      - Opportunity Award Program (Box 25)
      - Organizational Charts (Box 25)
      - Orientation, Office of (Tom Butts, Director) (Box 25)
      - Osteopathy (proposed school) (Box 25)
      - Ouimet Building (Box 25)
      - P-General (Box 25)
      - Parkes, David (Development Council) (Box 25)
      - Pay Policy (includes strike), 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Personnel Office (Box 25)
      - Pharmacy, College of (Tom D. Rowe, Dean) (Box 25)
      - Phi Sigma Award (Box 25)
      - Physical Education (Box 25)
      - Pierpont, W. K. (Vice President and Chief Financial Officer) (Box 25)
      - Policies (Box 25)
      - Policy: Deanship Search Committees (Box 25)
      - Porter, Dr. John W (Box 25)
      - Position Control in Academic Units (Box 25)
      - Power, Eugene (Box 25)
      - Power Exchange Scholar
        - Burdett, Jeremy K (Box 25)
        - Flight, Howard E (Box 25)
      - Power Exchange Scholarship (Box 26)
        - General (Box 26)
        - England (Box 26)
        - Publicity Problems (Box 26)
      - President's Report (Box 26)
      - Princeton Moratorium (Box 26)
      - Procedures (miscellaneous) (Box 26)
      - Project Outreach (Box 26)
      - Public Health, School of
        - Correspondence (Box 26)
        - Departments (Box 26)
        - Wegman, Myron E., Dean (Box 26)
      - Public Policy Studies, Institute of (IPPS) (Box 26)
      - Q-General (Box 26)
      - R-General (Box 26)
      - Racial Survey (Box 26)
      - Radock, Michael (Vice President for University Relations) (Box 26)
      - Raiding (Box 26)
      - Recruiting (Box 26)
      - Regents
        - Action Letters (Box 26)
        - Agenda (Box 26)
        - Budget (Box 26)
        - Bylaws
          - Chapter 7, 2 folders (Box 26)
          - Revision (Box 26)
          - Revision Committee (Box 26)
        - Communications (Box 26)
        - Correspondence
          - General (Box 26)
          - Brown, Robert J (Box 26)
          - Cudlip, William B (Box 26)
          - Dunn, Gerald R. (Box 26)
          - Goebel, Paul G (Box 26)
          - Huebner, Gertrude V (Box 26)
          - Nederlander, Robert E (Box 26)
          - Smith, Otis M (Box 26)
      - Registration and Records
        - Correspondence (Box 26)
        - Statistics (Box 26)
      - Religion, Studies in (Box 26)
      - Religious Affairs, Office of (Box 26)
      - Reporting Procedures (Box 26)
      - Report to University Community (Box 26)
      - Reserve Officers' Training Corps (ROTC) (Box 26)
      - Residency
        - General (Box 26)
        - Grievances, 4 folders (Box 295)
          [Student records restricted until July 01, 2055 ]
      - Residential College (Box 26)
        - General (Box 26)
        - Robertson, J., Dean (Box 26)
      - Resignations (Box 26)
      - Resources Allocation/Utilization (Box 26)
      - Retirement Furlough (Box 26)
      - Ross, Arthur, Vice President for State Relations and Planning (Box 26)
      - Russel (Henry) Lectureship (Box 26)
      - S-General (Box 26)
      - Sabbatical Leaves (Box 26)
      - Sain, Leonard (School of Education) (Box 26)
      - Sauve, Robert P. (Administrative Assistant) (Box 26)
      - Sea Grant Program (Box 26)
      - Security (Box 26)
      - Senate, University
        - Assembly (Box 26)
        - Committees
          - General (Box 26)
          - Academic Affairs Advisory Committee (Box 26)
          - Advisory Review Committee (Box 26)
          - Economic Status of the Faculty (CESF) (Box 26)
          - Research Policies (Box 26)
          - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA), 2 folders (Box 26)
        - Meetings (Box 26)
      - Social Work, School of
        - Correspondence (Box 26)
        - Dean's Correspondence (Box 26)
      - Space (Box 26)
      - Space Inventory (Box 27)
      - Space Utilization (Box 27)
      - Speech Clinic (Box 27)
      - Spurr, Stephen H
        - Position Papers (Box 27)
        - Vice President and Dean of Rackham School of Graduate Studies (Box 27)
      - Staff Benefits, Office of (Box 27)
      - State Board of Education (Box 27)
      - State Department of Education
        - General (Box 27)
        - Planning Division (Box 27)
      - State Legislature
        - General (Box 27)
        - Legislative Committees (Box 27)
      - State Plan for Higher Education in Michigan: Role of the U of M (Box 27)
      - Strike Policy (Box 27)
      - Student Affairs, Office of (Box 27)
      - Student Aid (Box 27)
      - Student Government Council (Box 27)
      - Students (Box 27)
      - Sunderland (Edson R.) Chair (Box 27)
      - T-General (Box 27)
      - Tarrant, Shawn (Assistant Director of University Housing) (Box 295)
      - Teaching Fellows, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Teaching Fellow/Research Assistant Data (Box 27)
      - Teaching Fellows Union, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Television (Box 27)
      - Television Instruction (Box 27)
      - Tenure, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Transfer of Funds (Box 27)
      - Tropical Studies, Organization for (OTS) (Box 27)
      - Trueblood Auditorium (Box 27)
      - Tuition (Box 27)
      - Turner, Roberta J. (re: study in Ghana) (Box 27)
      - Tuskegee Institute (Box 27)
      - Tutorial Project (Box 27)
      - U-General (Box 27)
      - U.S. Congress (Box 27)
      - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare
        - General (Box 27)
        - Compliance, Racial (Box 27)
        - Office of Civil Rights (Box 27)
        - Publications (Box 27)
      - University (general correspondence re:) (Box 27)
      - University Center for Adult Education, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - University Hospital
        - General (Box 27)
        - Financial Statements (Box 27)
        - Strike (Box 28)
      - University Housing (Box 28)
      - University Management Intercom (Box 28)
      - University Press, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - University Publications (Box 28)
      - University Relations (Box 28)
      - University School (Box 28)
      - Upward Bound (Box 28)
      - Urban (Box 28)
      - V-General (Box 28)
      - Vietnam (Box 28)
      - W-General (Box 28)
      - Wagner (Harvey A.) Professorship in Electrical Engineering (Box 28)
      - Waivers (Box 28)
      - Walgreen (Mary Ann and Charles R., Jr.) Endowed Chair (Box 28)
      - Wallace, James B. (Dean, School of Music) (Box 28)
      - Washtenaw County (Box 28)
      - Washtenaw County Community Mental Health Center
        - General (Box 28)
        - University Hospital Advisory Committee (Box 28)
      - Water Resources (Box 28)
      - Wayne State University (Box 28)
      - Western European Studies Committee (Box 28)
      - Williams, Robert L. (Administrative Dean, Academic Affairs) (Box 28)
      - Willow Run Laboratory (Box 28)
      - Wisconsin, University of (Box 28)
      - Women, Center for Continuing Education of (Box 28)
      - Yale University (Box 28)
      - Young (Arthur) Professorship (Box 28)
      - Zimmermann, Ernest R. (Assistant to VPAA), 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Zitta, Dr. Victor (Dept. of Political Science) (Box 28)
  - 1970-1971
    - Alphabetical Files
      - Academic Affairs Advisory Council (Box 28)
      - Allmand, Charles M. (Assistant to VPAA) (Box 28)
      - American Council on Education (ACE) (Box 28)
      - Architecture and Design, College of (Department of Architecture)
        - General (Box 28)
        - Accreditation (Box 28)
        - Ten-Year Plan (Box 28)
      - Black Students (Box 28)
      - Business Administration, School of
        - Bond, Floyd A., Dean (Box 28)
        - Bureau of Industrial Relations (Box 28)
      - Campus Conditions, Statement by Alexander Heard, Special Advisor to President Nixon, July 1970 (Box 28)
      - Cash, William (Asst. to the President for Human Relations Affairs) (Box 28)
      - Center for Research Libraries (CRL) (Box 28)
      - Center for Study of Higher Education (Box 28)
      - Day Care Center (Box 28)
      - Dearborn Chancellor Search (Box 295)
      - Doezema, Dr. Edward R. (complaint) (Box 295)
      - Educational Telecommunications System: Senate Bill 190 (Box 28)
      - Engineering, College of, Television Institute (Box 28)
      - Extension Service Dean Search (Box 295)
      - Faculty Reform Coalition (Box 28)
      - Financial Aid Office (Box 28)
      - Firearms (Box 28)
      - Fresh Air Camp (Box 28)
      - Graduate Studies, Rackham School of, Committee on Dean Search, 2 folders (Box 295)
      - Green (Edith) Formula (Box 29)
      - Haber, William (Adviser to Executive Officers) (Box 29)
      - Health Service (Box 29)
      - Institute for Social Research (ISR) (Box 29)
      - Institute for the Study of Mental Retardation (Box 29)
      - Institute of Public Policy Studies (IPPS) (Box 29)
      - Inter-University Consortium for Political Research (IUCPR) (Box 29)
      - Judiciary, University (Box 29)
      - King (Martin Luther) Fund (Box 29)
      - Knauss, Robert, Vice President for Student Services (Box 29)
      - Law School Dean Search (Box 295)
      - Lesch, J. E. (Assistant to VPAA) (Box 29)
      - Letters to Deans (Box 29)
      - Library Science (Box 29)
      - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of
        - Enrollment (Box 29)
        - Historical File (Box 29)
        - Reorganization (Box 29)
        - Sauve, Robert P. (Administrative Assistant) (Box 29)
        - Study (Box 29)
      - Lutheran Hospital (Box 29)
      - Massalias, Byron G. (faculty/staff complaint) (Box 295)
      - Medical School and Medical Center, Dean and Director Searches, 2 folders (Box 295)
      - Music, School of, Committee on Dean Search (Box 295)
      - National Defense Education Act (NDEA) Summer Program on South Asia (Box 29)
      - Norman, A. G., Vice President for Research (Box 29)
      - Pass-Fail Grading (Box 29)
      - Patent Policy (Box 29)
      - Periodic Health Appraisal Unit (PHAU) (Box 29)
      - Physical Therapy Accreditation (Box 29)
      - Policy
        - General, 2 folders (Box 29)
        - Deanship Search Committees (Box 29)
        - Disclosure of Faculty Records (Box 29)
        - Strike Policy (Box 29)
      - Political Activity, Princeton Plan (Box 29)
      - Power Exchange Scholarships (Box 29)
      - Recruiting (Box 29)
      - Regents' Bylaws: Chapters 2 and 11 (Box 29)
      - Residency (Box 29)
      - Retirement Furlough (Spivey Report) (Box 29)
      - Spurr, Stephen, Vice President and Dean of Rackham (Box 29)
      - Student Evaluation of Courses (Box 29)
      - Tenure (Box 29)
      - University Hospital, Report of Nursing Search and Study Committee (Box 29)
      - VanDerHout Case (re: class disruptions) (Box 29)
      - Women, Center for Continuing Education of (Box 29)
      - Women: Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (Box 29)
  - 1971-1972
    - Alphabetical Files
      - A-General (Box 29)
      - Academic Affairs Advisory Committee, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Academic Affairs Advisory Council (Box 30)
        - Agenda (Box 30)
        - Correspondence (Box 30)
        - Minutes (Box 30)
      - Academic Affairs, Office of (Box 30)
      - Academic Programs (List) (Box 30)
      - Accreditation (Box 30)
      - Acts (Box 30)
      - Administration Building (Box 30)
      - Admissions Cases, 4 folders
        - Law School (Box 296)
        - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of (Box 296)
        - Medical School (Box 296)
        - Nursing, School of (Box 296)
      - Admissions, Office of (Box 30)
        - Correspondence (Box 30)
        - Director Search, Committee on (re: procedures) (Box 30)
      - Affirmative Action Program (Box 30)
      - Afro-American Studies (Box 30)
      - Allmand, Charles M. (Assistant to VPAA) (Box 30)
      - Alumni Association (Box 30)
      - American Association of University Professors (AAUP) (Box 30)
      - American Council on Education (ACE)
        - Correspondence (Box 30)
        - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare Talks on Accreditation (Box 30)
      - American Indians (Box 30)
      - Appeal Procedures (Box 30)
      - Archaeology, Graduate Student Traineeships (Box 30)
      - Architecture and Design, College of, Department of Art (Box 30)
      - Area Centers (Box 30)
      - Association of American Universities (AAU) (Box 30)
      - Athletics, Board in Control of Intercollegiate Athletics (Box 30)
      - Audits, University (Box 30)
      - Awards (Box 30)
      - B-General (Box 30)
      - Bentley Chair (Box 30)
      - Bills, Legislative (Box 30)
      - Biological Station (Box 30)
      - Blacks (Box 30)
      - Botanical Gardens (Box 30)
      - Branch Campuses, Funding (Box 30)
      - Brinkerhoff, James (Box 30)
      - Brodsky, Iosif (recruitment) (Box 30)
      - Brown, Ronald (Box 30)
      - Budget (Box 30)
      - Budget Worksheets (Box 30)
      - Bureau of Industrial Relations (Box 30)
      - Business Administration, School of (Box 30)
      - C-General (Box 30)
      - Calendar, correspondence re: (Box 30)
      - California (Box 30)
      - Capital Outlay (Box 30)
      - Carnegie Commission on Higher Education (Box 31)
      - Cash, William, Jr. (Asst. to President for Human Relations Affairs) (Box 31)
      - Center for Afro-American and African Studies (CAAS) (Box 31)
      - Center for Chinese Studies (Box 31)
      - Center for Coordination of Ancient and Modern Studies (Box 31)
      - Center for Early Childhood Development and Education (Box 31)
      - Center for Human Growth and Development (CHGD), 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Center for Japanese Studies (Box 31)
      - Center for Population Planning (Box 31)
      - Center for Population Studies (Box 31)
      - Center for Research on Economic Development (CRED) (Box 31)
      - Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (CRLT) (Box 31)
      - Center for Research Libraries (CRL), 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Center for Research on Conflict Resolution (Box 31)
      - Center for Study of Higher Education (Box 31)
      - Center for Western European Studies (Box 31)
      - Centers: General (Box 31)
      - Chavis, John (Coordinator of Special Projects) (Box 31)
      - Chicano Students (Box 31)
      - Child Care Center, 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Christensen, Craig W. (General Counsel) (Box 31)
      - Church, Michael (Director of Cultural Activities, Extension Service) (Box 31)
      - Clippings Service (Box 31)
      - Coalition for the Use of Learning Skills (CULS) (Box 31)
      - Columbia University (Box 31)
      - Commission on Resource Allocation (Box 31)
      - Committees
        - General (Box 31)
        - External
          - International Exchange of Persons (Fulbright-Hays) (Box 31)
        - Internal
          - Broadcasting (Box 31)
          - Budget Administration (Box 31)
          - Budget Help (Box 31)
          - Communications Review (Box 31)
          - Computer Policy and Utilization (Box 31)
          - Conference on International Higher Education (Box 31)
          - Evaluation and Examinations (Box 31)
          - Faculty Rights and Responsibilities (Box 31)
          - Fees (Box 31)
          - Health Sciences (Box 31)
          - Honorary Degrees (Box 31)
          - Institutional Cooperation, Committee on (CIC) (Box 31)
          - Integrated Flexible Medical Curriculum (Box 31)
          - Intercollegiate Athletics, Board-in-Control of (Box 31)
          - Liaison with Detroit Public Schools (Box 31)
          - Minority Supportive Services Task Force (Box 31)
          - Opportunity Program, Advisory Committee (Box 31)
          - P and A Salary Study Steering Committee (Box 31)
          - Plant Extension (Box 31)
          - Retirement, Early (Box 31)
          - Review, School of Public Health (Box 31)
          - Special Salary Adjustments (Box 31)
          - University Lands Used for Instruction and Research (Box 31)
          - University Press Review (Box 31)
      - Community Colleges (Box 32)
      - Complaint Letters (Box 32)
      - Computer Equipment Requests (Box 32)
      - Computing Center (Box 32)
      - Conferences (Box 32)
      - Control of Data Institutes (Box 32)
      - Cowley, Anne P. (faculty/staff complaint) (Box 296)
      - Curtis, Mrs. Patricia (student complaint) (Box 296)
        [Student records restricted until July 01, 2057 ]
      - D-General (Box 32)
      - Daane, Roderick K. (General Counsel) (Box 32)
      - Davis, Margaret B. (faculty/staff complaint) (Box 296)
      - Dearborn Campus (Box 32)
        - General (Box 32)
        - Division of Engineering (Box 32)
      - Degrees (Box 32)
      - Dental Research Institute, 2 folders (Box 32)
      - Dentistry, School of
        - General (Box 32)
        - Accreditation (Box 32)
      - Development Council (Box 32)
      - Disruption (Box 32)
      - Distinguished University Professorships (Box 32)
      - E-General (Box 32)
      - Education, School of (Wilbur J. Cohen, Dean) (Box 32)
      - Faculty Workload (Box 32)
      - Endowed Chairs (Box 32)
      - Engineering, School of
        - General (Box 32)
        - Dean Search (Box 296)
      - Environmental Simulation Laboratory (Box 32)
      - Evans, W. Keith (Budget Systems Coordinator, Academic Affairs) (Box 32)
      - Exchange Programs (Box 32)
      - Executive Officers (Box 32)
      - Extension Service (Box 32)
      - External Degree Program (Box 32)
      - F-General (Box 32)
      - Faculty Reform Coalition (Box 32)
      - Fauri, F. F. (Vice President for State Relations and Planning) (Box 32)
      - Fenstemacher, William (Assistant to VPAA) (Box 32)
      - Financial Aid, Office of (Box 32)
      - Fincher, Larry (Assistant to Vice President for State Relations and Planning) (Box 32)
      - Fleming, R. W., President (Box 32)
      - Flint College (Box 33)
      - Ford Foundation: General Correspondence (Box 33)
      - Foundations (Box 33)
      - Freeze (Wage/Price) (Box 33)
      - Fricke, Benno (Bureau of Psychological Services) (Box 33)
      - Fund Raising Policy (Box 33)
      - G-General (Box 33)
      - Gerontology, Institute of (Wayne State and the U of M) (Box 33)
      - Graduate Assembly (Box 33)
      - Graduate Assistant Program (Box 33)
      - Graduate Studies, Rackham School of
        - General (Box 33)
        - Data Systems (Box 33)
        - Dean Search (Box 296)
      - Graduate Student Associateship Program (Box 33)
      - Grievance Appeal Procedures (Box 33)
      - H-General (Box 33)
      - Haber, William (Adviser to Executive Officers) (Box 33)
      - Handicapped Students (Box 33)
      - Hays, William L. (Associate Vice President for Academic Affairs) (Box 33)
      - Health Service (Box 33)
      - Housing, University (Box 33)
      - Humanities (Box 33)
      - I-General (Box 33)
      - ID Cards, Photo (Box 33)
      - Indian Studies, American Institute of (Box 33)
      - Individualized Instruction (Box 33)
      - Inquiries (Box 33)
      - Institute for Environmental Quality (Box 33)
      - Institute for Planning and Assessment of Alternative Futures (proposed) (Box 33)
      - Institute for Social Research (ISR) (Box 33)
      - Institute of Continuing Legal Education (Box 33)
      - Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (ILIR) (Box 33)
      - Institute of Public Policy Studies (Box 33)
        (see also "Public Policy Studies, Institute of")
      - Institutes-General (Box 33)
      - Institutional Research, Office of
        - General (Box 33)
        - Statistical Profile (Box 33)
      - International Center, Director Search (Box 296)